AKASH NAIR

Frankfurt am Main, Hesse +49 0176-323-76787 akashon1@gmail.com www.skywide.in

PERSONAL PROFILE

I am a DevOps engineer with nearly 3 years of experience on AWS, DevOps practices and scripting. I am seeking opportunities where I can use my skills to design and implement solutions that can improve and increase the velocity of software development

WORK EXPERIENCE

BlazeClan Technologies, India | Cloud Engineer

DECEMBER 2014 - JUNE 2016

Design of Highly Scalable and Fault Tolerant Architectures on the cloud
Migration of on-premise infrastructure to AWS
Configuration and troubleshooting of servers & networks
Implementation of server and network security measures
Optimisation of infrastructure and operations
Conducting routine security audits of systems and networks

Key Skills: AWS, Vagrant, Python, Linux/Unix, Cloud Migration, Disaster Recovery, Solution Architecture

PTC Software, India | Software Analyst

JULY 2016 - SEPTEMBER 2017

- ☐ Implementation of CI/CD pipelines for development teams using Jenkins
- ☐ Automation of processes and tasks using Python, Shell scripting
- ☐ Provisioning of infrastructure whenever required
- ☐ Configuration management using Ansible
- ☐ Ensuring smooth deployments to production and test systems

Key Skills: Jenkins, Ansible, Docker, Shell Scripting, SCRUM, VPN, Papertrail

EDUCATION

University of Pune, India | Bachelors in Computer Science

AUGUST 2009 - APRIL 2012

University of Pune, India | Master of Computer Applications

AUGUST 2012 - APRIL 2015

Frankfurt UAS, Germany I Masters in High Integrity Systems

OCTOBER 2017 - PRESENT

CERTIF	ICATIONS
Pytho	on Data Structures - University of Michigan on Coursera
	Certificate earned at Monday, March 7, 2016
Using	Python to Access Web Data - University of Michigan on Coursera
	Certificate earned at Monday, June 13, 2016
AWS	Certified SysOps Administrator – Associate
۵	Successfully completed the AWS Certification requirements and gained recognition as a AWS Certified Solutions Architect
ū	Certificate AWS-ASOA-6871
SKILLS	& INTERESTS
Skills:	
	Proficient in English writing and speaking
	Basic knowledge of German
	Arduino programming
	Java
	Terraform
	ELK Stack
Interes	ts:
	Solo travelling, playing guitar, hiking, meeting new people, reading history books, urban
	exploration